Denis Quaid

Mobile Phone: 078 99337595 Email: <u>denisq91@gmail.com</u> Website: <u>denisquaid.com</u>

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/denis-quaid

Summary:

I am a results oriented and diligent iOS developer with three years experience in software development. I make it my goal to create applications with the user in mind, creating applications with a useable and intuitive user interface. I also understand the importance of creating highly readable and easily maintainable source code along with good test coverage. I am constantly striving to learn new technologies and better myself as I work in an industry that is subject to constant change and I am always open to new ideas and ways of working.

Tools & Libraries:

I have experience with the following tools, libraries and languages:

Languages: Swift, Objective-C, Node.js, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Tools: Git (Github, Stash, Bitbucket, SourceTree), CocoaPods, Xcode, GOCD CI, Testflight, Npm **Libraries:** UIKit, AFNetworking, AlamoFire, XCTest, CoreData, Core Animation, Core Graphics

Work Experience:

YOOX NET-A-PORTER

iOS Developer

(March 2015 - September 2017)

As part of the NET-A-PORTER iOS team I worked within part of the mobile team to deliver features and bug fixes in line with the current roadmap. My primary achievements include:

- Inheriting a completely Objective-C based application with less than 20% test coverage, after two years on the team this was raised to 45% and the majority of the app was ported to Swift 3.
- Creating a contract test suite using the Jasmine framework (Javascript based) running nightly on a number of mac mini's to test important micro-services on which the app depended.
- Refactoring the previous analytics library in order to deliver a new library which conformed to the Customer Experience Digital Data Layer (CEDDL) which allows us to seamlessly port to different analytics providers. I also took on the role of analytics champion within my team which meant I was the first point of contact for all analytics related work.
- Delivering the first shoppable Apple TV application which was featured in Apple's Best of 2016.

THE NET-A-PORTER GROUP

Graduate Software Developer

(September 2014 - March 2015)

I began at Net-A-Porter as a graduate software developer where I worked within a front end web development team. I used this time to discover different software development languages and gain experience of working within an agile team of developers and testers. The languages I focused on were mainly Node.js and Java. My main responsibilities and achievements during this time include:

- Created an application to dynamically generate a number of sitemaps for different categories and product pages on the Mr Porter website using Node.js and Express.js
- Worked within an Agile team maintaining a legacy J2EE website using TDD and modern best practice principles.
- Wrote unit tests to contribute to the test suite within the team and being part of the release process as a manual tester.
- During this time I also completed a number of online courses in order to improve my knowledge of software design practises and different languages.

UniWink.com

IT Intern

(December 2013 - March 2014)

UniWink.com is a new business start-up founded by Sarah Dineen of UCC. We believe in the power of online peer assistant and social learning for third level students. UniWink.com is a website that will allow students to access and share lecture notes and course material with other top students. As an IT intern my roles include:

- Marketing on behalf of UniWink.com in order to grow the brand within UCC and Cork.
- Managing the Facebook and Twitter page of the company to interact with users.
- Maintaining control of the database as well as entering new data via SQL
- Regularly communicating with the IT director in order to make recommendations and receive updates on the website.
- Organising competitions and sponsorship opportunities for UniWink.com
 Inputting design ideas in order to help the website reach the maximum audience possible.

Education:

BSC Social Science (2010-2013)
University College of Cork
Graduated with Second Class Honours Grade One (2.1)

MBS Electronic Business (2013-2014)

University College of Cork Graduated with Second Class Honours Grade One (2.1)